A Finding Aid to the Will Barnet Papers, 1938-2001, in the Archives of American Art AAA.barnwill
Archives of American Art
Will Barnet papers
1938-2001
AAA.barnwill
Archives of American Art
11.1 Linear feet
The papers of painter, printmaker, and educator Will Barnet measure 11.1 linear feet and date from 1938 to 2001. Found within the papers are biographical material, including numerous recorded interviews of Barnet; personal and professional correspondence; writings and lectures; financial records; printed material; artwork; and photographs of Barnet, his family and friends, and his work.
Barnet, Will, 1911-2012
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Will Barnet donated his papers in several increments between 1968-2001.
Separated Materials note
Also found in the Archives are papers that were lent for microfilming (reels N68-22, N69-126, and N70-48.) Most but not all of this material was included in subsequent donations, except for scattered newsclippings and exhibition catalogs. The microfilm is not described in the container listing of this finding aid.
Related Archival Materials note
The Archives of American Art holds three oral history interviews with Will Barnet, one conducted by Richard Baker, January 20, 1964, one by Paul Cummings, January 15, 1968, and another by Stephen Polcari on April 9, 1993. Also found are two additional related collections, a transcript of an interview by Louis Newman with Molly Barnes and Will Barnet, and Peter Barnet's research material on Will Barnet. Syracuse University holds additional papers of Will Barnet.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Portions of the papers were microfilmed on reels N68-35, N69-46, and 98. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan but researchers are advised that the microfilm does not reflect the current order of the papers and is incomplete. One 8mm motion picture film of a 1966 exhibition at Hirschl and Adler (Series 1) was transferred onto video recordings (VHS and digital Betacam), which are available for research access at the Archives of American Art's Washington D.C. office. The original reel is not available for playback due to fragility.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical/Historical note
Will Barnet (1911-2012) was a painter, printmaker, and educator who lived and worked in New York City.
Barnet was born in Beverly, Massachusetts to Noah and Sarahdina Barnet. After showing an early interest and affinity for art, he attended the School of the Museum of Fine Arts in Boston. In 1931, he received a scholarship to attend the Art Students League where he studied with Stuart Davis and began building his printmaking techniques. In 1935, he was appointed the League's official printer, and was given his first teaching position there the following year. In 1938, working in the style of social realism, he held his first gallery show at the Hudson Walker Gallery in Manhattan. That same year, Barnet married Mary Sinclair, with whom he had three sons.
In the 1940s and 50s, Barnet began to move away from realism and started painting domestic familial subjects in geometric abstract styles, a move influenced by Native American and modern European art. By 1953, he had divorced and was remarried to Elena Ciurlys, with whom he had a daughter. Elena and his daughter were the subject of many of his representational, dimensionally flat paintings in the 1960s and 70s. During the 60s, Barnet also returned to large scale abstract art, and moved back and forth between styles throughout the rest of his career into the 2000s.
As an educator, Barnet taught graphic arts, printmaking, composition, and painting courses at the League from 1936 to 1980, and also taught courses Cooper Union, Yale, and the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts. He received numerous awards, including the first Artist's Lifetime Achievement Award given on the National Academy of Design’s 175th anniversary, the College Art Association’s Lifetime Achievement Award, and the 2011 National Medal of Arts.
Will Barnet died in his home in Manhattan, New York on November 13, 2012.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of painter, printmaker, and educator Will Barnet measure 11.1 linear feet and date from 1938 to 2001. Found within the papers are biographical material, including numerous recorded interviews of Barnet; personal and professional correspondence; writings and lectures, many of which exist only as audio and video recordings; financial records; printed material, including audio and video documentaries; artwork; and photographs of Barnet, his family and friends, and his work.
Biographical materials consist of appointment and address books, curriculum vitae, a fellowship application, awards ceremony documentation, and numerous recorded interviews, including a 9 part interview with Kitty Gellhorn conducted over the course of two years. Only 6 of the 24 interviews have transcripts and most are found only on original audio and video recordings with no duplicate access copies.
Correspondence is primarily with Barnet's family, friends, fellow artists, and business associates discussing personal relationships, teaching and lecturing appointments, gallery sales, and exhibitions. Correspondents of note include Cameron Booth, Henry Pearson, Angelo Savelli, Harry Sternberg, Jon Von Wicht, Esther Robles Gallery, and the Waddell Gallery (formerly Grippi and Waddell).
Writings by Barnet consist of 7 essays, 45 teaching lectures, 3 notebooks, and 4 speeches. Many of the lectures and 3 of the 4 speeches exist only as audio and video recordings for which there are no transcripts or duplicate access copies. The bulk of writings by others are biographical essays and memoirs of Barnet, including a copy of Peter Barnet's dissertation, Will Barnet: Artist and Teacher. The series also includes 4 exhibition guest registers.
Personal business records include sales and teaching contracts, gift acknowledgements, and price lists.
Printed material includes auction catalogs, clippings, audio recordings, video documentaries, exhibition announcements and catalogs, newsletters, press releases, programs, and reproductions of artwork. Video documentaries of note include Artist's Eye and Lasting Impressions, both of which Barnet contributed interviews to.
Photographic materials document people, artwork, exhibition installations, and works of art. There are early photos of Barnet teaching at the Art League, as well as photos of Barnet in his studio and with friends and family. Views of exhibition installations, award ceremonies, and events mainly document solo shows and Barnet's reception after receiving the National Arts Club's Gold Medal Award.
Artwork consists of ink, pencil, and pen sketches by Will Barnet, and a drawing by Bill Smith.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 7 series.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1945-1995 (2 linear feet; Boxes 1-2)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1940-2001 (3 linear feet; Boxes 3-5, OV 12)
Series 3: Writings, 1940-2000 (3.1 linear feet; Boxes 5-9)
Series 4: Personal Business Records, 1950-1981 (5 folders; Box 9)
Series 5: Printed Material and Publications, 1938-2001 (2.3 linear feet; Boxes 9-11)
Series 6: Photographic Materials, 1939-2001 (0.5 linear feet; Box 11, OV 12)
Series 7: Artwork, 1938-1983 (3 folders; Box 11)
Art Students League (New York, N.Y.); Barnet, Peter; Booth, Cameron, 1892-1980; Esther-Robles Gallery.; Pearson, Henry, 1914-; Savelli, Angelo, 1911-; Sternberg, Harry, 1904-2001; Von Wicht, John, 1888-1970; Waddell Gallery.; Art teachers; Artists' studios -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs; Interviews; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Photographs; Printmakers -- New York (State) -- New York; Sketches; Sound recordings; Transcripts; Video recordings; Visitors' books
- Biographical Materials, 1945-1995; Series 1; 2 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical materials consist of appointment and address books, curriculum vitae, a fellowship application, a video recording of an awards ceremony at Long Island University, and 24 interviews, six with transcripts. Interviewers include Karl Fortress, Sylvan Cole, and Kitty Gellhorn, who conducted a 9 part interview over the course of two years. There is also a recording of Will Barnet's children interviewing each other in reportage style. Audio and video recordings are on 6 videocassettes (VHS), 1 videocassette (U-matic), 1 videocassette (Betacam), 9 sound tape reels (1/4 in.), and 15 sound cassettes.
  Arrangement note
  Items are arranged by document type. Interviews are filed in chronological order.
  Existence and Location of Copies note
  The Hirschl and Adler interview and exhibition opening 8mm motion picture film has been transferred to VHS and digital Betacam for research access.
  - Address Books, circa 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appointment Books, 1968-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Awards Ceremony, Long Island University, 1995; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1971-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship Application, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Interview with Anne and Janet, circa 1950-1975; 2 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Interview with Colette Roberts, circa 1950-1970; 1 sound tape reels (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Interview with Karl Fortress, circa 1950-1970; 1 sound tape reels (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Interview with Unknown Interviewer (panal discussion), circa 1950-1970; 1 sound tape reels (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Interview with Casper Citron, 1965; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Interview and Exhibition Opening at Hirschl and Adler Gallery, 1966; 1 Videocassettes (Digital Betacam); 1 Videocassettes (VHS); 1 Film reels 8mm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Access copy available on VHS and digital Betacam cassettes.
  - Interview with M. Alexenberg, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Interview with WFLN-AM, "Know Your Art", 1969; 2 sound tape reels (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Interview with Unknown Interviewer (on Birch Wathen), circa 1970s; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Interview with Unknown Interviewer, circa 1970s; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Interview with Natalie Feldman, 1974; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Interview with Unknown Interviewer (on Dick Waddell), 1974; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Interview with Kitty Gellhorn, #1-4, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Interview with Kitty Gellhorn, #5-6, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Kitty Gellhorn, #7-8, 1976; 2 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Interview with Kitty Gellhorn, #9, 1976; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Interview with Artscene, 1981; 1 Videocassettes (U-matic) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Interview with Channel 13, 1982; 1 Videocassettes (Betamax) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Interview with Jacquie Saul, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Interview with Connie Goldman, 1986-1987; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Interview with Sylvan Cole, circa 1988; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Interview with Cathy Barnett, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Interview with Annette Scherman, 1988; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Interview with O'Farrell Gallery, 1988; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Interview with Joyce Johnson, 1990; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Interview with Ray Steiner, 1992; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Interview with Unknown Interviewer, 1995; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Will Barnet's Children Interviewing Each Other, 1968; 1 sound tape reels (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1940-2001; Series 2; 3 Linear feet Boxes 3-5, OV 12
  Correspondence is primarily with Barnet's family, friends, fellow artists, and business associates discussing personal relationships, teaching and lecturing appointments, gallery sales, and exhibitions. Correspondents of note include Cameron Booth, Henry Pearson, Angelo Savelli, Harry Sternberg, Jon Von Wicht, Esther Robles Gallery, and the Waddell Gallery (formerly Grippi and Waddell). There is substantial correspondence from mentored artists Christina Bothwell, George Lloyd, and Ik-Song Jin, and contemporary artist and friend Arnold Singer. The series also includes cards with original artwork sent by Barnet's friends.
  All correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, followed by unidentified, illegible, unsigned letters, and fragments.
  - A-Az, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Allentown Art Museum, 1973-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1956-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Arkansas Arts Centers, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Arpol Travel Agency, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Art Students League of New York, 1940-2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ascher, Mary, circa 1950-1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - ASPCA, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Associated American Artists, 1971-1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - B-Bz, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
  - Baranik, Rudolph and Stevens, May, 1963-1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Barnet Family, circa 1950-2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Barnet, Will, circa 1950-1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Barr, Daisy, 1963-1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Billotte, Bill, 1968-1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Booth, Cameron, 1949-1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Bothwell, Christina, 1980-2001 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - Boyle, Richard J., 1962-1997 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1955-1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - C-Cz, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - Century Association, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Cincinnati Art Museum (Boyle, Richard), 1956-1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Columbia University (Gellhorn, Walter), 1970-1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Committee of Religion and Art in America Inc. (Vatican), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Cooper Union, 1964-1999 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1960-1968 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Cornell University, 1966-1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - D, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1999 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Day, Worden, 1964-1976 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Denyer, Ted, 1967-2000 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - E, Miscellaneous, circa 1960-1999 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Eastern Washington State Historical Society, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Esther Robles Gallery, 1957-1963 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Eyerly, Frank, 1969-1982 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - F, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1999 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Faiers, Edward Spencer (Ted), 1955-1978 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    Includes a thesis with a chapter on Barnet by Constance Wolfe.
  - Famous Artists Schools, 1953-1975 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Farrell, James T., 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Fisher, Ethel, 1962-1999 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Ford Foundation, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Freeman, Mrs. Gaylord, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - G-Gz, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Galleria Trastevere, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Green, Eric, 1995-1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Grippi and Waddell Gallery, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Guggenheim Museum, 1956-1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - H-Hz, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
  - Haass, Terry, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hirschl and Adler, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - I, Miscellaneous, circa 1965-2000 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Institute of Contemporary Art (Levitt, Janice), 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - J, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Jin, Ik-Song, 1990-1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - K, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Kane, Robert and Eva, circa 1950-1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - L, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Levitt, Janice, 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Library of Congress, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Lloyd, George, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - M-Mz, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
  - MacDonald, Jock, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Mary Harriman Gallery, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Masurovsky, Gregory, 1987-2001 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Mayer, Bena Frank, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Memphis Academy of Arts, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1950-1987 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1954-1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1945-2000 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - N, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - National Academy of Design, 1976-1999 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Neuberger Museum, 1975-1991 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Nevelson, Mike, 1971-1998 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Nicoll, Marion and Jim, 1957-1981 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - O, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - P, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Pearson, Henry, 1960-1994 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1950-1990 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Print Club, 1952-1987 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - R, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Romano, Clare and John, 1968-2001 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - S-Sz, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Savelli, Angelo, 1959-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
  - Scoville, Jonathan A., 1969-1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Singer, Arnold, 1966-2000 (Box 5, Folder 8-11)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1967-1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Sternberg, Harry, 1978-2000 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Sullivan, Tom, 1967-1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Syracuse University, 1964-1987 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - T, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Taft, Stan, 1967-1998 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - U, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - University of Minnesota (Boyce, William), 1958-1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - University of Notre Dame, 1963-1967 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - V, Miscellaneous, circa 1955-1999 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Vogel, Dorothy and Herb, 1976-1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Von Wicht, John, 1946-1972 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Vranesh, George, 1962-1998 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - W, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Waddell Gallery, 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Wechsler, Elaine, 1989-1999 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - White House, 1962-1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Whitney Museum, 1940-1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Wichita State University, 1971-1975 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Wingate, George, 1979-2001 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Woodward, Hildegard, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - X-Z, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2000 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Zutrau, Ed, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Cards, Birthday, circa 1990-2000 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Cards, Original Artwork, circa 1970-1999 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Oversized material housed in OV 12.
  - Unknown and Illegible, circa 1950-2000 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Oversized Cards, Original Artwork from Box 5, Folder 37, circa 1970-1999 (Box OV 12)
- Writings, 1940-2000; Series 3; 3.1 Linear feet Boxes 5-9
  Writings by Barnet consist of 7 essays, 45 teaching lectures (14 with transcripts), 3 notebooks, and 4 speeches.
  Lectures include "Personal Reflection on the Spiritual Aspects in American Art" given at the Vatican, a series of 22 taped lectures given at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts between 1970 and 1973, and a draft notebook of a proposed work on color lithography. Barnet's lecture recordings are on 4 videocassettes (VHS), 18 sound tape reels, and 25 sound cassettes. Only 14 of the 45 lectures have transcripts. Most are found only on original audio and video recordings. Three of the four speeches by Barnet are recorded on 1 VHS videocassette and 2 audio tape reels.
  The bulk of writings by others are biographical essays and memoirs of Barnet, including a copy of Peter Barnet's dissertation, Will Barnet: Artist and Teacher, and a copy of Katherine Kuh's essay, "Sitting for Will." This subseries also includes 4 exhibition guest registers and creative fiction by others, including a play and poems. A portion of the writings by others are recorded on 1 videocassette (VHS) and 2 sound cassettes.
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  3.1 By Will Barnet, 1945-1998
  3.2 By Others, 1940-2000
  - By Will Barnet, 1945-1998; 3.1
    - Essay, "Aims in Teaching", circa 1960-1975 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Essay, "Aspects of American Abstract Painting", 1956 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Essay, "Creative Approach to Graphic Arts", circa 1960-1975 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Essay, "Future Directions", circa 1960-1975 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Essay, "My Philosophy of Art", circa 1960-1975 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Essay, "My Self Portrait", circa 1960-1983 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Essay, "Painting Without Illusion", circa 1960-1975 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Essay Drafts, circa 1950-1980 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Lecture, "20th Century: American Contemporary Artists", 1958; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Lecture, "20th Century: Leger and Juan Gris", 1958; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Lecture, "Abstraction in Old Masters", 1963; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Lecture, Art Students League, 1998; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Lecture, Art Survey (slide show), 1969; 1 sound tape reels (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Lecture, "Color as Form", 1958; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Lecture, "Horizontal and Vertical", 1958; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Lecture, "Ingres, Memling, Poussin", 1961; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Lecture, "Ingres, Van Gogh, Gauguin, Matisse, and Utamaro", 1957; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Lecture, "My Work", 1958 June 27; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Lecture, "My Work", 1958 August 5; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Lecture, "Old Masters and Composition", 1988; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Lecture, On Artistic Practice, 1975; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Lecture,"On Rembrandt", 1965; 1 sound tape reels (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Lecture,"Personal Reflection on the Spiritual Aspects in American Art", 1976 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Lecture,"Portrait and Abstract Art", 1969; 1 sound tape reels (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Lectures, Pennsylvania Academy of the Arts, circa 1970-1973; 22 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Lecture, "Space", 1958 July 3; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Lecture, "Space", 1961 February 2; 1 sound tape reels (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lecture, "Survey of Painting", 1958; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Lecture, Truro Congregational Church, 1990; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lecture, "Two Spatial Concepts", 1961; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Lecture, "Vermeer", 1958; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Lecture, Woodstock School of Art (slide lecture), 1992; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Lecture Notes, circa 1950-1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Notebook, Art Notes, circa 1950-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Notebook, Color Lithography Book Contents, 1945-1949 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Notebook, Color Lithography Book Cover, 1945-1949 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Notebook, Neuberger Exhibition List, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Speech, At ASL Dinner Honoring Barnet and Julian Levi, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Speech, "Aspects of the Modern Portrait", circa 1950-1970; 1 sound tape reels (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Speech, Honoring Lou Zorna, 1996; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 7)